Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.17
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Ongoing Career, 1993; XVII.
  - Foreign Trips, 3.
    - International Republican Institute (IRI) Russian Election Monitoring Mission, December 7-15, 1993
      - Pre-trip material: news releases following Attorney General USSR trip (October 14-20, 1989), December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 1)
      - Pre-trip material: correspondence and interview requests (in Moscow), December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 2)
      - Pre-trip material: planning documents and list of confirmed delegates, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 3)
      - Pre-trip material: "Delegation Report: IRI Monitoring Mission to the Referendum in the Russian Federation," published by the IRI, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 4)
      - Pre-trip material: Kazakhstan parliamentarian's visit to the United States to discuss the U.S. legislative system and its possibilities in Central Asia, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 5)
      - Pre-trip material: letter to Thornburgh from Thomas Reems regarding Veniamin Yakovlev's visit to the U.S. for planning conference "The Legal Defense of Entrepreneurship, Judicial Reform, and the Developing Commercial Code in Russia", December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 6)
      - Pre-trip material: "Report on the Ethnic Conflict in the Russian Federation and Transcaucasia," a Strengthening Democratic Institutions Project of Harvard University's Kennedy School of Government, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 7)
      - Pre-trip material: Russia election candidates briefing in The Financial Times, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 8)
      - Pre-trip material: election observer briefing materials and Thornburgh's notes, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 9)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing material and background on Russia's politics and elections, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 10)
      - Pre-trip material: flight and hotel information and tickets, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 11)
      - Trip material: IRI welcome folder (includes trip itineraries, emergency procedures, talking points and Russia briefings), December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 12)
      - Trip material: trip itinerary, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 13)
      - Trip material: press conferences and interviews, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 14)
      - Trip material: "Translation of Decisions of The Central Election Commission of the Russian Federation," prepared by the International Foundation for Electoral Systems (IFES), December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 15)
      - Trip material: IRI news release, "Republican Parliamentary Election Observation Mission Preliminary Statement", December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 16)
      - Trip material: memorabilia and invitations, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 17)
      - Trip material: Thornburgh's notes regarding trip, talking points and election fact sheet, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 18)
      - Trip material: trip diary, "Russia Votes: A Monitoring Undertaking by the IRI, Dick Thornburgh's Journal of the Events Surrounding the Historic Elections of December 12, 1993", December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 19)
      - Post-trip material: election results and news articles, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 20)
      - Post-trip material: "List of Deputies Elected to the Federal Assembly of the Russian Federation," prepared by the IRI, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 21)
      - Post-trip material: press conference talking points, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 22)
      - Post-trip material: correspondence with Russian officials and U.S. Senator John McCain, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 23)
      - Post-trip material: print media coverage of the IRI Election Observation Mission as of February 2, 1994, and corresponding articles, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 24)
      - Post-trip material: Thornburgh article, "Election Observation Mission to Russia," IRI newsletter, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 25)
      - Post-trip material: Thornburgh Op-Ed, "How Russia can Make its Next Elections Fairer," The Washington Times, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 26)
      - Post-trip material: report on the Moscow and Saratov jury trials, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 27)
      - Post-trip material: "IRI Election Observation Mission Report," draft, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 28)
      - Post-trip material: "IRI Election Observation Mission Report," final copy, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 29)
      - Post-trip material: Rule of Law Consortium, Newly Independent States (NIS) Rule of Law (ROL) Program to support processes of democratization, December 7-15, 1993 (Box 986, Folder 30)
    - Trip to Russia, October 24, 1995
      - Pre-trip material: Judiciary, due process and the Russian Commercial Courts briefing material, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 1)
      - Pre-trip material: Russia briefing materials from the IRI, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 2)
      - Pre-trip material: "Russia's Tinderbox: Conflict in the North Caucasus and Its Implications for the Future of the Russian Federation," a Strengthening Democratic Institutions Project of Harvard University's Kennedy School of Government, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 3)
      - Pre-trip material: "Steel Imports from Russia and their Implications for Steel Markets," a Congressional Research Service Report, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 4)
      - Pre-trip material: "Looking Beyond Moscow: Doing Business in Central Asia, Ukraine, and the Russia Far East" conference, Boston, MA, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 5)
      - Pre-trip material: newsletters from the Heritage Foundation regarding Russia, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 6)
      - Pre-trip material: travel documents and customs declaration forms, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 7)
      - Trip material: hotel welcome sheet, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 8)
      - Trip material: "Commercial Law Judicial Training," published by the International Law Institute (ILI) and Georgetown University (in Russian), October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 9)
      - Post-trip material: correspondence, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 10)
      - Post-trip material: "Yeltsin's Anti-reform Policies: Kow-towing to Cronyism," report by the Maldon Institute, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 11)
      - Post-trip material: newsletters from the Heritage Foundation regarding Russia, October 24, 1995 (Box 987, Folder 12)
    - International Republican Institute (IRI) Russian Election Monitoring Mission, June 10-18, 1996
      - Pre-trip material: letter from IRI and request to join election observation mission, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 13)
      - Pre-trip material: IRI news release regarding international election observation mission to Russia, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 14)
      - Pre-trip material: Correspondence to Russian officials from Cuyler Walker regarding Thornburgh's visit, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 15)
      - Pre-trip material: delegate briefing meeting, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 16)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing material, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 17)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing material, "Press and Editorial Comments on Russia's Presidential Elections", June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 18)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing material, "Regional Profile--Moscow," and letter regarding regional observation deployments, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 19)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing material on the observation mission from the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe of the European Union's (EU) Office for Democratic Institutions and Human Rights, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 20)
      - Pre-trip material: travel arrangements (including visas, flights, hotel and meal accommodations), June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 21)
      - Pre-trip material: Forum for International Policy issue brief, "The Russian Presidential Election: Epochal or Prosaic?", June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 22)
      - Pre-trip material: National Security Telecommunications Advisory Committee, presentation by Arnaud de Borchgrave on global organized crime and Russia, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 23)
      - Pre-trip material: Federal Law Articles on the activities of election observers during the election of President of the Russian Federation, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 24)
      - Trip material: trip itineraries and schedules, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 25)
      - Trip material: press conference briefing material, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 26)
      - Trip material: talking points and possible questions and answers, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 27)
      - Trip material: IRI news release regarding improvement of democracy in Russian elections, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 28)
      - Trip material: IRI Election Observation Mission's preliminary statement, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 29)
      - Trip material: Thornburgh's notes regarding trip, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 30)
      - Trip material: Trip diary, "Russia Elects a President: Round One, A Journal of the Election Monitoring Mission to the Russian Federation of the IRI, Dick Thornburgh, Co-chairman", June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 31)
      - Trip material: memorabilia, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 987, Folder 32)
      - Post-trip material: correspondence (including to Veniamin Yakovlev), June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 1)
      - Post-trip material: "20 Most Asked Questions" and answers, prepared by the International Foundation for Electoral Systems (IFES), June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 2)
      - Post-trip material: IRI briefing on Russian presidential election and assessment from trip delegates, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 3)
      - Post-trip material: "The Civil Code of the Russian Federation," with introduction by Veniamin Yakovlev, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 4)
      - Post-trip material: Invitation to Thornburgh to participate in International Bar Association's 6th Eastern European Regional Conference, "Russian Law in Transition: The International Perspective", June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 5)
      - Post-trip material: "Restructuring Aid to Russia: Revising H.R. 4426," Issue Bulletin, newsletter of the Heritage Foundation, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 6)
      - Post-trip material: Russian American Business Center as law client, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 7)
      - Post-trip material: "IRI Election Observation Mission Report," draft and final copy, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 8)
      - Post-trip material: "Protocols and Vote Summaries of Russia's Presidential Election: Round 1, June 16, 1996," prepared by IRI, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 9)
      - Post-trip material: "Protocols and Vote Summaries of Russia's Presidential Election: Round 2, July 3, 1996," prepared by IRI, June 10-18, 1996 (Box 988, Folder 10)
    - Russia News Clippings and Articles (from all trips)
      - News clippings, 1991-1997 (Box 988, Folder 11-16)
      - The Moscow Times newspapers, 1993-1996 (Box 988, Folder 17)
      - The Moscow Tribune newspapers, 1993-1996 (Box 988, Folder 18)
    - Publications and Journals regarding Russia (from all trips)
      - "Windows of Opportunity: From Cold War to Peaceful Competition in U.S.-Soviet Relations," a joint statement of the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University and the Soviet Academy of Sciences, January 29, 1984 (Box 989, Folder 1)
      - "Perestroika and the Procuracy: The Changing Role of the Prosecutor's Office in the Former USSR," a U.S. Department of Justice, Bureau of Justice Statistics (BJS) paper, February, 1992 (Box 989, Folder 2)
      - "Surviving Together: A Journal on Relations with the Former Soviet Union," published by the Institute for Soviet-American Relations (ISAR), Winter, 1992 (Box 989, Folder 3)
      - "U.S. Relations with Russia, Ukraine, and Eastern Europe," Aspen Institute Conference booklets, 1992-1995 (Box 989, Folder 4)
      - Vedernikov, Nikolai T. and O.N. Vedernikova, "Problems of Constitutional Jurisprudence and the Formulation of a 'Rule of Law' State in Russia," Saint Louis University Law Journal, Vol. 38, No. 4, Summer, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 5)
      - East European Constitutional Review, Vols. 3-4, 1994-1995 (Box 989, Folder 6)
      - "Russia's National Security State," a report by the Maldon Institute, July 19, 1995 (Box 989, Folder 7)
      - Russia: Economy and Politics magazine, published by the Gorbachev Foundation, 1995 (Box 989, Folder 8)
      - Amcham News, Vol. 3, No. 10, published by the American Chamber of Commerce in Russia, March-April, 1996 (Box 989, Folder 9)
      - "Russia on the Eve of the Presidential Election: A Staff Report to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the U.S. Senate", May, 1996 (Box 989, Folder 10)
      - McFaul, Michael, "Russia Between Elections: What the December 1995 Results Really Mean," published by the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1996 (Box 989, Folder 11)
    - International Republican Institute (IRI) Rule of Law Mission to Hong Kong, June 12-19, 1994
      - Pre-trip material: travel arrangements (including visas, flights, hotel and meal accommodations), June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 12)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing material, including Thornburgh's notes on Rule of Law, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 13-14)
      - Pre-trip material: "Hong Kong: America's Business Partner in Asia" briefing material, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 15)
      - Pre-trip material: correspondence, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 16)
      - Pre-trip material: IRI luncheon featuring Martin C.M. Lee, chairman of the United Democrats of Hong Kong, speaking on democracy and Rule of Law in Hong Kong (introduced by Thornburgh), June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 17)
      - Pre-trip material: invitation to attend presentation of speaker John Kamm, resident of Hong Kong and active spokesman for U.S. economic interests in the territory, presentation sponsored by the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 18)
      - Pre-trip material: "The Sino-British Joint Declaration on the Question of Hong Kong," agreement signed by Margaret Thatcher and Zhao Ziyang, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 19)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing on the jailing of Hong Kong journalist Xi Yang in China, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 20)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing on popular Hong Kong political personalities (including Emily Lau), June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 21)
      - Pre-trip material: testimony of Emily Lau on Hong Kong's elections and democracy in the territory, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 22)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing on Hong Kong press freedom and corresponding legislation, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 23)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing on Hong Kong's legal system and legal aid, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 24)
      - Pre-trip material: "Asia and Pacific Decade of Disabled Persons, 1993-2002: The Starting Point," published by ESCAP (of the United Nations), June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 25)
      - Trip material: trip itineraries and schedules, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 26)
      - Trip material: "Hong Kong's Bill of Rights, 1991-1994, and Beyond," a seminar organized by the Faculty of Law at the University of Hong Kong, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 27)
      - Trip material: "The Rule of Law in Hong Kong ... Today and Tomorrow," remarks by Dick Thornburgh to the American Chamber of Commerce in Hong Kong, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 28)
      - Trip material: Thornburgh's notes regarding trip, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 989, Folder 29)
      - Trip material: trip diary, "The Rule of Law in Hong Kong ... Today and Tomorrow: A Journal of the Visit to Hong Kong by Dick Thornburgh for the IRI", June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 1)
      - Trip material: trip memorabilia, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 2)
      - Post-trip material: correspondence and invitations, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 3)
      - Post-trip material: "A Blow to Hong Kong's Future," The Washington Post, an Op-ed by Thornburgh, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 4)
      - Post-trip material: U.S. Senate Congressional Record congratulating Martin C.M. Lee on receiving the 1995 International Human Rights Award by the American Bar Association Litigation Section, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 5)
      - Post-trip material: "Hong Kong's Future is Being Decided Now," unpublished article by Thornburgh, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 6)
      - Post-trip material: "Hong Kong's Countdown to 1997," unpublished article by Thornburgh, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 7)
      - Post-trip material: Statement of Dick Thornburgh to Subcommittee on East Asian and Pacific Affairs, Committee on Foreign Relations of the U.S. Senate, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 8)
      - Post-trip material: testimonies of others to Subcommittee on East Asian and Pacific Affairs, Committee on Foreign Relations of the U.S. Senate, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 9)
      - Post-trip material: "America's Stake in Hong Kong," Asian Studies Center Backgrounder, No. 137, newsletter of the Heritage Foundation, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 10)
      - Post-trip material: biography on Roderick [B]un Woo for meeting with Dick Thornburgh, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 11)
      - Post-trip material: Newsletter, published by the Embassy of the People's Republic of China, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 12)
      - Post-trip material: "International Espionage for Commercial Advantage" paper by Davis B. Bobrow and Robert T. Kudrle, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 13)
      - Post-trip material: IRI Rule of Law Mission to Hong Kong report, draft and final copy, June 12-19, 1994 (Box 990, Folder 14)
    - National Democratic Institute (NDI) Pre-election Mission to Hong Kong, March 15-18, 1998
      - Pre-trip material: invitation to participate in Hong Kong mission, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 15)
      - Pre-trip material: travel arrangements, including flights and hotel, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 16)
      - Pre-trip material: list of participating delegates, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 17)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing material on trip, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 18)
      - Pre-trip material: "Guidelines on Election-Related Activities in Respect of 1998 Legislative Council Elections," prepared by the Electoral Affairs Commission, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 19)
      - Pre-trip material: final report of the IRI Rule of Law Mission to Hong Kong (dated June, 1994), March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 20)
      - Pre-trip material: Thornburgh's trip diary from IRI Rule of Law Mission to Hong Kong and remarks to American Chamber of Commerce in Hong Kong (dated June, 1994), March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 21)
      - Pre-trip material: "Hong Kong's 'Sham' Democracy," unpublished article by Dick Thornburgh, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 22)
      - Pre-trip material: "The Rule of Law in Hong Kong: Some Implications for U.S. Policy," article by Dick Thornburgh, University of Pennsylvania Journal of International Economic Law, Vol. 18 No. 1, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 23)
      - Pre-trip material: correspondence, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 24)
      - Pre-trip material: "Six-month Report on Hong Kong, July-December 1997: Presented to Parliament by the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs by the Command of Her Majesty," published in Britain, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 25)
      - Pre-trip material: "Introducing the University of Hong Kong," briefing, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 26)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing materials on the Better Hong Kong Foundation, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 27)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing materials on the Hong Kong Policy Research Institute (HKPRI), March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 28)
      - Pre-trip material: briefing materials on the Provisional Legislative Council (PLC) of Hong Kong, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 29)
      - Pre-trip material: legal cases in Hong Kong and Rule of Law matters, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 30)
      - Pre-trip material: news releases from Hong Kong's Democratic Party regarding Rule of Law, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 31)
      - Trip material: preliminary statement of the NDI delegation, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 32)
      - Trip material: press coverage and interview requests for Thornburgh, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 33)
      - Trip material: Thornburgh's notes regarding trip, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 34)
      - Trip material: memorabilia, March 15-18, 1998 (Box 990, Folder 35)
      - NDI reports pre and post 3/98 mission, including 3/98 led by Dick Thornburgh, 1997-1998 (Box 990, Folder 36)
    - Trip to Hong Kong, January 10-16, 1999
      - Trip material: itineraries and schedules, January 10-16, 1999 (Box 991, Folder 1)
      - Trip material: Thornburgh's notes regarding trip, January 10-16, 1999 (Box 991, Folder 2)
      - Trip material: trip diary (handwritten), January 10-16, 1999 (Box 991, Folder 3)
      - Post-trip material: correspondence, January 10-16, 1999 (Box 991, Folder 4)
    - Hong Kong News Clippings and Articles (from all trips)
      - News clippings, 1992-1998 (Box 991, Folder 5-10)
      - South China Morning Post, 1994-1998 (Box 991, Folder 11)
    - Publications and Journals regarding Hong Kong (from all trips)
      - "Obscene Articles Tribunal," published by the Hong Kong Administrative Region Government, 1987 (Box 991, Folder 12)
      - "Legal System in Hong Kong," produced by Legal Department of the Hong Kong Government, April, 1991 (Box 991, Folder 13)
      - Publications regarding Hong Kong Bill of Rights, published by the Faculty of Law at University of Hong Kong, 1991-1999 (Box 991, Folder 14)
      - "Hong Kong's Transition: Problems and Prospects," published by the Faculty of Law at University of Hong Kong, November 28, 1992 (Box 991, Folder 15)
      - Turning Point, published by Hong Kong Confederation of Trade Unions, January, 1994 (Box 991, Folder 16)
      - On the Record, Vols. 1-2, published by the Hong Kong Journalists Association, January-May, 1994 (Box 991, Folder 17)
      - China Labor Bulletin, issue 2, April, 1994 (Box 991, Folder 18)
      - Far Eastern Economic Review, June 16, 1994, June 23, 1994 (Box 991, Folder 19)
      - "New Hong Kong Law Boosts U.S. Firms," Lawyer International, no. 23, August, 1994 (Box 991, Folder 20)
      - "Hong Kong Journalists Association 26th Anniversary Bulletin", 1994 (Box 991, Folder 21)
      - United States-China Relations: Notes from the National Committee, Vol. 23 No. 2, Winter, 1995 (Box 991, Folder 22)
      - "The Future of Hong Kong," The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, September, 1996 (Box 991, Folder 23)
      - Hong Kong Circle, published by the Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office in Washington, DC, Vol. 1 No. 8, June-July, 1997 (Box 991, Folder 24)
      - "No Hong Kong Deal for Taiwan," Asian Studies Center Backgrounder, No. 151, August 4, 1997 (Box 991, Folder 25)
      - "Prospectus," University of Hong Kong, 1997-1998 (Box 991, Folder 26)
    - That All May Worship," Education and Rehabilitation Exchange Foundation (EREF) Trip of Ginny and Dick Thornburgh to the Republic of Korea, June 12-19, 1995
      - Pre-trip material: briefing materials saved from Attorney General's trip to Tokyo and Seoul, August 31-September 7, 1990, June 12-19, 1995 (Box 991, Folder 27)